http://www.troyleedesigns.com/pages/privacy-policy

Store Locator
You are ${ shippingDifference | toUSD } away from free shipping
You have FREE shipping
Taxes will be calculated at checkout.
+ Add
Your cart is currently empty.
Your Privacy Is Important to Us
Troy Lee Designs values your privacy, and is committed to protecting your personal information. This privacy policy ("Policy") applies to Troy Lee Designs, LLC, and its subsidiary and affiliate companies (collectively, "Troy Lee Designs," "we," "us," or "our"). This Policy explains our practices regarding the personal information we collect from you or about you through our website or apps, or through your written or verbal communications with us, including information collected offline  (collectively, our “Services”). This Policy applies whenever you use our Services.
PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT
HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
HOW WE USE INFORMATION
HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION
OUR SERVICES ARE NOT INTENDED FOR CHILDREN
YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS
NEVADA PRIVACY NOTICE
INFORMATION SECURITY
PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT
Personal information is information that can be used to identify you (whether alone or in combination with other information). We collect personal information through your interactions with our Services.
The personal information we collect includes:
Name Information (first, middle, last, alias, title, username);
Email Address;
Email Communication Preferences;
Postal Address (including both shipping and billing addresses);
Phone Number;
Birthdate and Age;
Gender;
Physical Characteristics (such as measurements and sizes for helmets and apparel)
Geolocation Data;
Preferences;
Payment Information (including credit and debit card information);
Purchase History, Wishlist Items, and Products Viewed or Considered;
Customer Reviews and Photos;
Communications Sent by Phone, Email, Mail, Text, Fax, or Online Chat;
Email Engagement Activity;
Advertising Interactions;
Troy Lee Designs Stone Rewards Loyalty Program Information (status, join date, interactions, tier name, spend to next tier, lifetime points, available points, points to next reward, last earned points, points expiration, available rewards, reward earned date, last activity date, referral interactions);
Product Registration, Warranty, and Recall Information;
IP Addresses;
Social Media Login Information;
Information From Cookies, Pixels, Web Beacons, HTTP Referrers, and Other Tracking Technologies (IP addresses, cookie ID; browser user ID; account utoken; domain; browser ID; browser GUID; browser information; language preference; device ID; other unique device identifiers; device type; device model; platform; operating system type information; advertising interactions; website browsing behavior (such as pages viewed on our website and the websites you list before and after ours, search history, click tracking, and access date, time, and duration); web log information; and geolocation data). For our full Cookies Policy, please click here [link ]);
Website Analytics Information;
Information Contained in Applications for Employment With Us. Click here for our Notice to California Job Applicants [link];
Inferences About You From All of the Above (for example, we may infer whether you are a mountain biker, moto rider, or both based on the products you purchase from us).
HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
We collect your personal information through various means, including when you directly provide information to us and when we automatically collect information about you through your use of the Services. In some instances, you may be able to choose what information to provide, but sometimes we require certain information for you to use certain features of the Services.
Information You Provide to Us
We may collect personal information you provide directly to us, including:
When you shop for our products online or in our stores;
When you, or someone on your behalf, provides information to us in order to:
Register or maintain an account with us;
Find the best-fitting products (e.g., by providing information about your physical traits or riding style);
Register the products you purchase from us or make warranty claims for those products;
Sign up for the Troy Lee Designs Stone Rewards program;
Post comments to our online communities;
Apply for employment with us;
Obtain technical support;
Participate in a survey, marketing promotion, sweepstakes or contest; or
Connect with us via social media.
Through business partners, distributors, resellers and suppliers;
When you communicate with us by mail, email, text, phone, fax, or online chat.
Information We Collect Automatically
By their nature, our websites and apps also automatically collect some personal information about you when you use our Services. Examples of the types of personal information that may be collected automatically when using the Services include:
IP addresses;
Information from cookies, pixels, web beacons, HTTP referrers, and other tracking technologies;
Pages you view within our website, search terms you enter, and other actions you take while visiting us;
Webpages you view immediately before and after you access our Services;
Information related to whether you’ve opened an email or clicked on a link contained in an email;
Information from a referring source (a search engine, advertisement, blog, social media site, etc.);
Website analytics information;
Information from content you post or share publicly on discussion forums or other social media pages (including the content you post, your name, and a link to your profile).
Cookies and Similar Technologies: We and our Service Providers may use cookies or other tracking technologies (such as web beacons, tracking pixels, and HTTP referrers) to collect and store information about interactions with the Services, including information about your browsing and purchasing behavior. Cookies are small files that a website or its service provider transfers to a computer’s hard drive through a web browser that enable the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize the user’s browser, and capture and remember certain information. In general, we and our third-party providers use cookies and other tracking technologies to optimize the functionality of the Services, to help us understand how the Services are used, and to provide users with interest-based content or advertising based upon their browsing activities.
If you would like to opt-out of cookies, visit www.aboutcookies.org or www.allaboutcookies.org for further information. These sites also provide details on how to set your browser not to accept cookies and how to remove cookies from your browser. In a few cases, some of the features of our Services may not function if you remove or delete Cookies. More information on how we use cookies can be found in our Cookies Policy [link].
Website Analytics Information: We use Google Analytics to ensure website functionality and improve the Services both on the web and on mobile devices. This software may record information such as your IP address, location, and age, browser type and language, operating system, access time, duration of visit, pages you view within our website, search terms you enter and other actions you take while visiting us, the pages you view immediately before and after you access the Services, how often you use the Services, aggregated usage and performance data, app errors and debugging information, and where the Services were downloaded from. Google Analytics is owned and controlled by Google LLC. Data collected by Google is subject to its privacy policy. To learn about how Google uses data related to website analytics when you use our site or apps, click here: [Add link: https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites]. You may opt-out of having your activity on our website made available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics browser add-on, available here [Add link: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout].
HOW WE USE INFORMATION
We may use your personal information for the purposes described below.
Type of Personal Information or Data
Purpose(s) for Which We Use This Information
Name and Contact Information (including your first name, middle name, last name, alias, title, username, email address, email communication preferences, postal address, phone number, etc.)
To fulfill orders and deliver your purchases To handle returns To send you order updates through email and text messages To send you information on products and articles with your permission To detect and prevent fraud against you and/or us To show you relevant ads while you are browsing the web or using social media To contact you in order to obtain information about your product preferences and how we can improve our products and business
Birthdate and Age
To detect and prevent fraud against you and/or us
Gender and Physical Characteristics (such as measurements and sizes for helmets and apparel)
To help you find gear that fits you To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates To help you find relevant products more quickly
Payment Information (including credit and debit card information)
To fulfill orders and provide refunds To detect and prevent fraud against you and/or us
Purchase History, Wishlist Items, and Products Viewed or Considered
To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates To help you find relevant products more quickly To provide customer service and support To handle returns
Customer Reviews and Photos
To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates To provide customer service and support To improve our products and business
Communications Sent by Phone, Email, Mail, Text, Fax, or Online Chat
To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates To learn how we can improve our products and business To provide customer service and support To handle returns To provide training to our staff
Device and Usage Information        (such as geolocation data, IP addresses, etc.)
To make it easier for you to log into our website To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates
To help you find relevant products more quickly To show you relevant ads while you are browsing the web or using social media To improve our website, set default options, and provide you with a better shopping experience To protect the security of our website To detect and prevent fraud against you and/or us
Email Engagement Activity and Advertising Interactions
To show you relevant ads while you are browsing the web or using social media To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates To count ad impressions, and correlate them with unique visitors To verify positioning and quality of ad impressions To learn how we can improve our products, business, and website
Stone Rewards Loyalty Program Information
To reward you for being a loyal Troy Lee Designs customer To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates To learn how we can improve our products and business
Product Registration, Warranty, and Recall Information;
To communicate with you regarding recalls for registered products To learn how we can improve our products and business
Information and Photos You Provide in Connection With Any Request for Custom Paint or Lettering
To process your request for custom painting or design work To provide you with a quote for custom painting or design work
Responses to Surveys, Competitions, Promotions, and Sweepstakes
To learn how we can improve our products and business To provide you with opportunities to win awesome stuff
Sponsorship Information
To evaluate you for sponsorship
Event Registration Information
To communicate with you about events we host, sponsor, or promote To send you information on products and articles with your permission To show you relevant ads while you are browsing the web or using social media
To contact you in order to obtain information about your product preferences and how we can improve our products and business
Social Media Login Information
To register you for an account with us To make it easier for you to log into our website To help you connect and share content with your friends and followers To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates
To help you find relevant products more quickly To send you information on products and articles with your permission
Information From Cookies, Pixels, Web Beacons, HTTP Referrers, and Other Tracking Technologies
To make it easier for you to log into our website To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates
To help you find relevant products more quickly To show you relevant ads while you are browsing the web or using social media To improve our website, set default options, and provide you with a better shopping experience To protect the security of our website To detect and prevent fraud against you and/or us
Website Analytics Information
To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates
To help you find relevant products more quickly To show you relevant ads while you are browsing the web or using social media To improve our website, set default options, and provide you with a better shopping experience To protect the security of our website To detect and prevent fraud against you and/or us
Employment Applications
Please see our Employment Application Policy [link]
Inferences About You
To provide you with appropriate products, recommendations, and updates
To help you find relevant products more quickly To show you relevant ads while you are browsing the web or using social media To improve our products, business, and website To protect the security of our website To detect and prevent fraud against you and/or us
Publicly Available Information
Any purpose
We may use information for any purpose if the information does not identify you, and cannot be combined with other information accessible to us to identify you.
HOW WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION
In order to provide you with the best products and services, we share your personal information among our contractors, business partners, service providers, and other third parties as described in this section. When we share personal information, we require that the parties we share it with use the information only in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.
We share your personal information as follows:
Related Organizations. We may share some or all of your personal information with our parent and subsidiary companies and companies under shared corporate control;
Service Providers. We may from time to time use business partners, suppliers, contractors, and sub-contractors ("Service Providers") to assist us with the provision of services to us (for example, without limitation, website hosting, app design, maintenance services, database management, web analytics, app analytics, billing, payment processing, fraud protection, credit risk reduction, marketing, or improvement of services). These Service Providers have access to your personal information only to perform the respective tasks assigned to them on our behalf, and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.
Compliance with Laws. We may share your personal information as necessary, for the following purposes: (a) to comply with any legal process; (b) to respond to requests from public and government authorities; (c) to enforce our terms and conditions; (d) to protect our operations and protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of you or others; and (e) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.
Insurers and Professional Advisors. We may share your personal information with our insurers and professional advisers for the purposes of managing risks, obtaining professional advice, exercising or defending against legal claims, etc.
Sale or Transfer of Business or Assets. We may share or transfer some or all of your personal information with third parties in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition or dissolution transaction, reorganization, joint venture, or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture, termination or transfer of all or part of our business, assets, or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings). In the event of any of the foregoing, personal information may be transferred as a business asset.
Other Legitimate Business Purposes. We may also disclose your personal information to our distributors, resellers and suppliers for business purposes. For example, we may share your personal information to process your orders, fulfill your requests, provide customer service, and improve our products and services.
Co-Marketing. We may share your personal information with third parties for co-marketing purposes, to improve our product recommendations and Services, or to provide you with other products and services;
Advertising. We may share your personal information with other sites, including social media platforms and advertising partners (such as Google and Facebook) for the purpose of ad targeting, remarketing, and customized advertising content.
OUR SERVICES ARE NOT INTENDED FOR CHILDREN Our Services are neither intended for, nor targeted to, children under the age of sixteen (16). We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 16. If we learn that we possess information from a child under the age of 16, we will delete such information in accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) and other applicable laws. If you are a parent or guardian and you believe that your child under the age of 16 has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us at customerservice@troyleedesigns.com.     YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS Under the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 and certain other California privacy and data protection laws, you have the right to submit certain requests relating to your personal information, as described below.   Right to Know
If you are a California resident, you have the right to request more information regarding the following, to the extent applicable:
The categories of personal information we have collected about you in the preceding 12 months.
The categories of sources from which the personal information was collected.
The business or commercial purpose why we collected or, if applicable, sold your personal information.
The categories of third parties with which we share personal information.
The specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you.
The categories of personal information about you that we have shared with third parties for a business purpose in the preceding 12 months, and for each category, the categories of third parties to which we disclosed the information (if any).
A list of all third parties to whom we have disclosed personal information, as defined under California Civil Code Section 1798.83(e) (a/k/a the “Shine the Light Law”), during the preceding year for third-party direct marketing purposes.
You may submit a request for the information above by calling us at (800) 239-6566, emailing us, or submitting a completed form available here.  In connection with submission of your request, we will take steps to verify your identity as outlined below, and you will need to verify your identity before action is taken.
Please note that due to the different requirements of the applicable laws, our response times may vary depending on the specific type(s) of information sought.  We respond to all verifiable requests for information as soon as we reasonably can, and no later than legally required.
Right to Request Deletion of Your Personal Information
Subject to certain exceptions, and upon your submission of a verifiable request, California residents have the right to deletion of their personal information from our records, and to have us direct our service providers delete your personal information from their records.   Once we receive your request, we will let you know what, if any, personal information we can delete from our records, and we will direct any service providers that may have collected personal information about you through our website to delete your personal information from their records. There may be circumstances where we cannot delete your personal information or direct service providers to delete your personal information from their records.  For example, if we need to: (1) retain your personal information to complete a transaction or provide services; (2) detect security incidents; (3) protect against unlawful activities; (4) identify, debug or repair errors; or (5) comply with a legal obligation. You may submit a request to delete your personal information by calling us at [insert toll free telephone number], emailing us at [insert email address], or submitting a completed form available here [insert link to web form]. In connection with submission of your request, we will take steps to verify your identity as outlined below, and you will need to verify your identity before action is taken.   Right to Opt Out of the Sale of Your Personal Information California residents have the right to opt out of the sale of their personal information. Although we do not sell your personal information to third parties for money, we do engage in activities—such as targeted advertising—that could be considered a “sale” under California law. To opt-out of the sale of your personal information, visit our homepage and click here, call us at 800-239-6566 or email us here.  Verification of Requests for Further Information or to Delete Personal Information Please note that when submitting a request to know or a request to delete information, you will be asked to provide information to verify your identity before action is taken. Verification is required in order to confirm that the person submitting the request to know or request to delete is the person to whom the information relates, and to prevent unauthorized access or deletion of information. The specific steps taken to verify the identity of the requesting person may vary based on the nature of the request, including the type, sensitivity and value of the information requested, the risk of harm posed by unauthorized access or deletion, the likelihood that fraudulent or malicious actors may seek the information, the robustness of personal information provided to verify your identity, the nature of our business relationship with you, and available technology for verification.  We will generally try to avoid requesting additional information from you for the purpose of verification, but we may need to do so if we cannot verify your identity based on the information already maintained by us. If we request additional information to verify your identity, it will be for that purpose only, and will be deleted as soon as practical after processing the request, except as otherwise provided by law. You may designate an authorized agent to make the requests below on your behalf. An authorized agent must submit proof to us that he or she has been authorized by you to act on your behalf, and you will need to verify your identity directly with us through the process described below. The following generally describes the verification processes we use:
Password Protected Accounts. If you have a password-protected account with us, we may use existing authentication practices to verify your identity, but will require re-authentication before disclosing or deleting data. If we suspect fraudulent or malicious activity relating to your account, we will require further verification (as described below) before complying with a request to know or delete.
Verification for Non-Accountholders. If you do not have, or cannot access, a password-protected account with us, we will generally verify your identity as follows:
For requests to know categories of personal information, we will verify your identity to a reasonable degree of certainty by matching at least two data points provided by you with reliable data points maintained by us.
For requests to know specific pieces of personal information, we will verify your identity to a reasonably high degree of certainty by matching at least three data points provided by you with reliable data points maintained by us. We will also require a declaration, signed under penalty of perjury, that the person requesting the information is the person whose information is the subject of the request or that person’s authorized representative. We will maintain all signed declarations as part of our records.
For requests to delete personal information, we will verify your identity to a reasonable degree or a reasonably high degree of certainty depending on the sensitivity of the personal information and the risk of harm posed by unauthorized deletion. We will act in good faith when determining the appropriate standard to apply.
If there is no reasonable method by which we can verify your identity, we will state so in response to a request to know or delete personal information, including an explanation of why we have no reasonable method to verify your identity.
Right to Non-Discrimination for the Exercise of Your Privacy Rights
If you choose to exercise any of the privacy rights conferred by the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018, you also have the right not to receive discriminatory treatment by us. This means that, consistent with California law, we will not deny providing our products or Services to you, charge you different prices or provide a different level or quality of products or Services to you unless those differences are related to the value of your personal information.
Nevada Privacy Notice
Under Nevada law, Nevada residents who have purchased goods or services from us may opt-out of the “sale” of “covered information” to third parties, as defined by Nevada law, including but not limited to name, address, social security number, and online service activity. Our uses of your personal information are not sales under Nevada law, so no opt-out is required.
INFORMATION SECURITY
The security of your personal information is important to us. We take commercially reasonable and appropriate safeguards to secure and protect the privacy, accuracy, and reliability of your information and to protect it from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the security of our systems or databases. Nor can we guarantee that the personal information we collect about you will not be breached, intercepted, destroyed, or accessed without authorization.
Please do your part to help us keep your information secure by choosing passwords carefully, keeping your password and computer secure (such as by signing out after using the Services), and changing your password from time to time.
INFORMATION STORAGE
We will retain your personal information only for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes set out in this Privacy Statement, for as long as your account is active, as needed to provide our Services to you, to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, or to enforce our agreements.
EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS
You may unsubscribe from our marketing communications by clicking the “unsubscribe” link found in every  marketing email we send, or (if you have an account with us) by logging into your account and changing your preferences, or by sending us a request to unsubscribe here. If you opt-out of receiving marketing email communications, we may still send you email messages related to your account with us, including specific transactions or our services. Unsubscribing yourself from our marketing communications will not affect our service to you.
TEXT MESSAGING
You have the choice to opt-in to receiving text messages and alerts on the mobile phone number(s) you have shared with us. Once you have opted-in, we may send you text messages (i) regarding your account; (ii) to investigate or prevent fraud; and (iii) to alert you in the event of an emergency. We may send you text messages and alerts using autodialed technology. We will not contact you via text messages or alerts for marketing purposes without your prior express written consent. You do not have to opt-in to text messages and alerts to use and enjoy our website and Services. If you opt-in, standard text messaging charges may apply. For more information regarding our text messaging and alerts, please contact us here or call 1-800-239-6566.
You may choose to opt-out from our text messages and alerts at any time using any reasonable means. To directly opt-out, send us a text message from your mobile phone with the word STOP, STOP ALL, END, QUIT, CANCEL or UNSUBSCRIBE, and we will unsubscribe you from text communications. Once you opt-out, you will not receive any additional text messages via your mobile phone. Please keep in mind that if you opt-out of receiving text messages and alerts we may not be able to contact you with important messages regarding your account. However, if there is an emergency or account question, we will make every attempt to contact you in other ways, such as by email or on a landline phone.
DO NOT TRACK
We do not currently have the technology to automatically respond to “Do Not Track” (DNT) signals sent by web browsers, mobile devices, or other mechanisms. You also may limit certain tracking by disabling cookies in your web browser. If you are a California resident who wishes to delete your personal information or opt out of the sale of you personal information, please see the instructions for submitting such requests, above.
LINKS TO THIRD-PARTY SITES
Our websites and apps may contain links to other websites or apps. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other websites or apps. You should read the privacy statements of these other websites or apps to understand their policies and practices.
PRIVACY POLICY UPDATES
We may update this Policy from time to time, in our sole discretion to reflect our current privacy practices. When we do so, we will post the new Policy on our website, and email existing customers at the email addresses associated with their accounts. Our use of personal information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time the information is provided or collected. You should consult this Policy regularly for any changes. Continued use of our Services following the effective date of any modification to the Privacy Policy constitutes your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the changes.
CONTACT
If you have questions or comments regarding this Policy or our treatment of your personal information, you may contact us at:
Troy Lee Designs
155 E. Rincon Street
Corona, CA 92879 USA
www.troyleedesigns.com
Phone: 951-371-5219
WHAT’S NEW
Effective January, 2020, we changed our Privacy Policy to clarify the types of information we collect about you, the ways we collect your information, and how we use and share your information. We also added a section to our Privacy Policy that explains the rights of California residents under the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018. Finally, we re-formatted our Privacy Policy to make it easier to read, and better enable you to find the information you are looking for.
Our Privacy Policy is now divided into many short sections so that you can quickly find what you need:
Your Privacy Is Important to Us
This section reflects the fact that we value your privacy and are committed to protecting it.
Personal Information We Collect
Clearly describes in a new list format the types of personal information we collect about you.
How We Collect Your Personal Information
This section describes the methods we use to collect personal information about you. Some of this is information you provide directly. We collect other information automatically—for example, through your use of our websites.
How We Use Information
This section includes a new chart that clearly describes how we use each category of personal information that we collect.
How We Share Information
This section includes descriptions of how we share your personal information, including with our Service Providers, and in order to show you relevant, targeted ads when you browse the internet or use social media.
Our Services Are Not Intended for Children
Makes clear that our Services are not intended for, or targeted to, children under the age of 16.
Your California Privacy Rights
This section describes your rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 and under the Shine the Light Law of 2005. It includes a description of how California residents can exercise their privacy rights.
Nevada Privacy Notice
Contains information for Nevada residents interested in exercising their right to opt out of the sale of their personal information. Our uses of your personal information are not sales under Nevada law, so no opt-out is required.
Information Security
An updated description of how we keep your data safe.
INFORMATION STORAGE
Explains how, and for how long, we maintain personal information.
Email Communications
This section contains all the information you need to manage your email preferences, including how to opt-out of marketing emails.
Text Messaging
Includes simple instructions on how to opt-in and opt-out of receiving text messages from us.
Do Not Track
Although some web browsers have the ability to send “Do Not Track” signals, our website does not have the ability to automatically respond to these signals.
LINKS TO THIRD-PARTY SITES
Our Privacy Policy describes our practices regarding how we treat your personal information. Please be careful whenever you visit someone else’s site, as their practices may be different from ours.
PRIVACY POLICY UPDATES
This section contains a reminder to check our Privacy Policy periodically for future updates.
CONTACT
Describes how to get in touch with us about privacy questions.
TROY LEE DESIGNS155 E. Rincon StreetCorona, CA 92879 USAMon-Fri, 8am - 5pm PSTTelephone: +1 (951) 371-5219Toll Free: +1 (800) 239-6566International: +1 (844) 824-8774
